<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dsquery on Perpetuum informatio - Never ending IT story</title><link>https://trukhanov.com/tags/dsquery/</link><description>Recent content in dsquery</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>Page(/tags/dsquery)</managingEditor><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 10:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/dsquery/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Association between virtual ethernet and virtual switch</title><link>https://trukhanov.com/2017/10/association-between-virtual-ethernet-and-virtual-switch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 09:24:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trukhanov.com/2017/10/association-between-virtual-ethernet-and-virtual-switch/</guid><description>&lt;p>You’ve just created couple of internal network switches in your Hyper-V Manager. Or you’ve just installed Docker for Windows and played with it a little. Now want to create NAT to allow your fresh new containers and/or virtual machines to have access to the Internet. Unfortunately there is no simple way to say which of the HNS Internal NIC adapters associated with proper vSwitch.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Script for Windows storage audit</title><link>https://trukhanov.com/2017/06/script-for-windows-storage-audit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 13:04:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trukhanov.com/2017/06/script-for-windows-storage-audit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve created PowerShell script to collect all important information about windows physical disks, partitions and volumes (logical disks) and its connections.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Windows storage hierarchy explained</title><link>https://trukhanov.com/2017/06/windows-storage-hierarchy-explained/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 10:23:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trukhanov.com/2017/06/windows-storage-hierarchy-explained/</guid><description>&lt;p>Quick cheat sheet:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Physical disk, represented by Win32_DiskDrive and MSFT_Disk WMI classes. This is hardware presented to your computer. It is HDD, SSD, FC LUN or iSCSI LUN.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Partition, represented by Win32_DiskPartition and MSFT_Partition WMI classes. Partitions are walls that transforming your physical space into rooms, which later can be used to store your data. Physical disk can have 0 or more partitions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Volume, represented by Win32_Volume and MSFT_Volume WMI classes. Volumes are named spaces, from abstract rooms you get living room, kitchen and bedrooms. You format room to make it “named room”. Or in other words, you format partition to some file system, i.e. NTFS, FAT or ReFS. Volumes can store data and provide access to it. One partition can have 0 or 1 volume. When partition has 0 volume, in most cases this means that there is no data accessible by user.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>“The update is not applicable to your computer”</title><link>https://trukhanov.com/2016/12/the-update-is-not-applicable-to-your-computer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 09:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trukhanov.com/2016/12/the-update-is-not-applicable-to-your-computer/</guid><description>Recently I’ve needed to apply 2 patches to our Windows 2008 R2. But both patches show me error “The update is not applicable to your computer”. But I knew for sure, that these updates were applicable, because installed file’s version was lower than the one contained in hotfixes.
In Setup log I’ve got “Windows update could not be installed because of error 2149842967” error.
The problem was that someone disabled Windows Modules Installer service on this machine, which is TrustedInstaller.</description></item><item><title>Install RemixOS on Hyper-V virtual machine</title><link>https://trukhanov.com/2016/01/install-remixos-on-hyper-v-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 15:30:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trukhanov.com/2016/01/install-remixos-on-hyper-v-virtual-machine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes you just need quickly deploy Android x86 server in your production environment using Microsoft Hyper-V virtualization. Now you can do it with &lt;a href="http://www.jide.com/en/remixos-for-pc">Remix OS&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Installation to Hyper-V virtual machine is a bit tricky, but possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unattended install for Microsoft Dynamics CRM 2015 Outlook Add-In</title><link>https://trukhanov.com/2015/09/unattended-install-for-microsoft-dynamics-crm-2015-outlook-add-in/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 13:42:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trukhanov.com/2015/09/unattended-install-for-microsoft-dynamics-crm-2015-outlook-add-in/</guid><description>&lt;p>To make fully unattended install package you need to do following steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Download install package: &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=45015">http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=45015&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Extract package content:&lt;br>
&lt;code>CRM2015-Client-ENU-i386.exe /extract:c:\CRM_TEMP\1\2&lt;/code>&lt;br>
Do not remove sub folders 1 and 2 from the path, because we need it later&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Create Redist folder in c:\CRM_TEMP. Do not put it in the sub folders&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Limit group policy only to client OS</title><link>https://trukhanov.com/2015/09/limit-group-policy-only-to-client-os/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 12:49:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trukhanov.com/2015/09/limit-group-policy-only-to-client-os/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes you want to apply your policy to every client PC in many OUs. To do such you can use WMI filter. This is especially useful in messy AD structures, where is no dedicated OU for client computer objects.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Namespace: root\CIMv2
Query: select * from Win32_OperatingSystem where ProductType=&amp;#34;1&amp;#34;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Can’t access any Outlook tabs on ribbon except Enterprise Vault</title><link>https://trukhanov.com/2015/09/cant-access-any-outlook-tabs-on-ribbon-except-enterprise-vault/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 12:37:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trukhanov.com/2015/09/cant-access-any-outlook-tabs-on-ribbon-except-enterprise-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently one of our customers installed Microsoft Dynamics CRM Outlook add-in and discovered that after this action Microsoft Outlook became absolutely useless, because after start of the program there are no other tabs except Enterprise Vault, which is also used by this customer. Little research showed that the root of the problem is in some components of earlier version of Microsoft Office. To fix problem you need to delete following registry key:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>HKEY_CLASSES_ROOT\TypeLib\{2DF8D04C-5BFA-101B-BDE5-00AA0044DE52}\2.4&lt;/code>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Random data big file creation</title><link>https://trukhanov.com/2015/08/random-data-big-file-creation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 14:54:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trukhanov.com/2015/08/random-data-big-file-creation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes you just need a big file. For example to test network speed, of backup speed. And to prevent software of hardware compression you need this file to be absolutely random. Also you do not want to write this file byte by byte, as it can be really slow. Here is my version of powershell script to generate such file:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TMG 2010 and “RPC Server unavailable”</title><link>https://trukhanov.com/2015/07/tmg-2010-and-rpc-server-unavailable/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 12:21:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trukhanov.com/2015/07/tmg-2010-and-rpc-server-unavailable/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I have encountered strange TMG behavior. I have permitted all RPC connections to Domain Controllers with system rule and disabled RPC Filter plus switched off “Enable strict RPC compliance” option. But my WMI requests and any other RPC traffic from TMG servers to internal resources was still blocked.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>